Scott Skender

303-304-7650 sjskender@gmail.com scottskender.com twitter.com/scottskender github.com/vandosant linkedin.com/in/scottskender

Profile

A Ruby and Rails developer with a passion for collaboration, pair-programming and test-driven-development. I have experience with deployment, databases, design, and more.

I have a background marketing to consumers, with a focus on digital advertising. Transferring my experience to web development means that I strive to deliver a remarkable experience to users.

Code

LANGUA — LANGUA.HEROKUAPP.COM // GITHUB.COM/VANDOSANT/LANGUAGE-APP

A Ruby on Rails project that interacts with translation API's. It features vocabulary, word translation, and saving translations. I manage data with PostgreSQL and dynamically save translations with JavaScript.

GAME OF LIFE — GAMEOFLIFE.SCOTTSKENDER.COM // GITHUB.COM/VANDOSANT/GAME-OF-LIFE

An ongoing exercise in thinking deeply about good design principles. I especially focused on expressing intent with my code, which led to smaller boxes for classes and methods.

PERSONAL SITE — SCOTTSKENDER.COM // GITHUB.COM/VANDOSANT/GSCHOOL-BLOG

I built this site in Middleman so that I could learn about building static websites. I have also found real enjoyment blogging about what I have learned.

Experience

DIGITAL MARKETING MANAGER, REAL GOODS SOLAR, LOUISVILLE, CO — 2013-2014

REGIONAL MARKETING MANAGER, REAL GOODS SOLAR, DENVER, CO — 2010-2013

MARKETING MANAGER, LIGHTHOUSE SOLAR, BOULDER, CO — 2008-2010

Education

gSchool, Boulder — Full Stack Development Immersive, March - August 2014
University of Georgia, Athens — Bachelor of Business Administration, Management, 2006